Let me share my screen.
OK, so am I audible loud and clear?
Yes.
OK,
so the item that we will be covering
today is ABC.
Then the time zone inconsistency stuff.
OK, schema group and collate.
The focus would be on the ABC and UTC.
If time permits,
you can we'll cover these two.
Otherwise we,
we will take it up in the next session.
OK, now any questions?
OK,
before even if we start the discussion,
any questions from the last sessions on
any of the items that we discussed?
OK, I'll take that as a no.
So now starting on the ABC.
So the thing here is you have a link here,
it opens the folder.
So here you have some documents, OK.
So this talks about the LLD, OK,
That is a Word document which talks about
all the activities that has happened
across the phases, OK.
And then this is one more document that
talks about the scenarios that we have
considered,
let's say in a period data scenario for
success restart,
we run incremental catch up how the
conflict table,
the ETL injection window should look like.
And so,
so and these are these document talks
about basically how the tables should be
populated during each of the scenario.
I will go in depth in a bit.
Let me first show you what each of these
documents contain.
OK, now this UID generation is nothing.
This is how we are gonna generate the UID
through the Arora inbuilt function.
So that is what it talks about.
This is the alignment that we have taken
and this document talks about that.
So nothing much on this document.
Data share,
this document you see it separately
because there's some discussions going on
how to handle data share,
you know how to tune,
tune AVC for the data share.
So as that discussion is going on and we
don't have a conclusion yet.
So these items track separately once we
get a closure,
I tried to collate this information
within it.
OK,
so so the reason of saying that is so
whatever we have close on ABC,
you'll see everything in this document
and in this document,
whatever ongoing that is data share I've
kept with a set.
And this is a discussion or this is a
recording that we had recorded during the
client discussions with LM where we had
given them are in depth ABC 2.
So this doc this this recording is about
it.
OK, and let's move on.
And you have this lucid even the document
has a lucid link which shows you the
entire framework that has been coded as
part of the ABC framework.
OK, any questions up till here?
OK.
And let me move on.
So now starting with ABC framework, OK,
Now what does that ABC framework mean?
It is audit balancing control.
So basically just think in this way,
every single job across any waves, OK,
that we will be executing it has to be
integrated within this framework, OK?
So that the headache of having the counts,
managing the counts,
the execution process,
you don't have to deal with that as part
separately as part of the job execution,
OK,
The framework itself will take care of it.
But integrating the framework within the
execution process is the work that we
have to do, OK?
But the framework is capable enough to
take the counts, to fail the job,
to restart the job,
whatever the scenarios,
I'll be talking in a bit.
So the framework is capable,
but the effort that we have to put here
is integrating the framework with our job
execution, OK?
So for so good, OK,
Now there is one more catch to it,
the effort again,
another activity that we would be doing
here is your entire framework.
OK executes based on some static
information that you give in the metadata
table.
So we have around 6/5 to six to seven
around metadata tables which hold the
information for each job execution.
Now let's say I'll go one by one through
all the metadata tables.
You have one table called as batch
metadata.
OK, Now what is batch?
What is job?
Batch is just thing as umbrella.
All the jobs that has to be triggered as
part of a batch, OK.
I mean all the jobs that has to trigger
as part of the batch comes under the
batch information.
For an example,
let me go with asset example.
Let's say you have a asset called as HR
OK,
let's say HR has 20 jobs to be triggered.
So HR as a batch goes into a metadata
table and the 20 jobs within the HR goes
into a job metadata tables.
OK, if there are any execution rules, any,
you know, critical DQ rules,
whatever you have to execute that goes as
part of a job rule assignment table,
What type of unique DQ checks?
Let's say you are doing null checks.
Let's say you are doing date checks.
Let's say you are doing whether my data
is available or not.
Some,
you know the checks that we are doing
across all the jobs that we do that goes
into a master list, OK.
Now if you have to do some balancing
control,
basically balance reconciliation is a
system where you reconcile the amount,
let's say your source is giving you for a
given job $100, OK,
the output should also give you $100.00.
So the intent here is whether you filter,
whether you pass through,
whether you do aggregation,
whether whatever you do,
if $100 enter your system,
your $100 should pass through your system.
OK,
the balance reconciliation metadata or
the functionality around this topic helps
us to evaluate that and capture that.
And there is also threshold let's say if
let's say 2-3 dollars here there maybe
there's acceptable range.
If that happens within the acceptable
range, then well and good.
If it is reaches the acceptable range,
then it fails.
So the intent of the balance
reconciliation is to do a reconciliation
on your amount fields.
This is very much specific to your amount
column.
So that is why this exercise right now
we're doing where we're trying to figure
out what all amount columns we have
across all the jobs,
across all the tables or across all the
waves.
This is the reason because the intent is
all the amount column has to be
reconciled.
The count checks is different.
Count is not the balance.
Balance is your amount.
OK that is just as a thumb rule.
Just remember that.
OK so these are some of the metadata
tables that is needed to hold your
information to execute your runtime
tables.
So far so good.
Any questions up till here?
So I might have a question regarding this
balance reconciliation.
What should be the idle threshold value
we should incorporate?
It depends.
That is something that business has to
give.
That is something we cannot, you know,
think through.
At times I've seen where one person,
you know, threshold is fine to them.
I've even seen cases where one person is
too much for them.
So it depends how much threshold they
want to give or take for a column
depending upon the business criticality.
If these are premium fields loss kind of
information, claim kind of information,
even a pending matters to them.
OK.
But if,
if there are some percentage type of
stuff, OK, at least in this project,
we don't go with percentage,
but at least I've seen balance
reconciliation happening on percentage,
but one or two,
35 percentage here they they're also fine.
OK.
So it depends upon the business
criticality of that column, not it.
OK, so that is why you have a threshold.
So the calculation has happened in a way
that does the math and checks against
this threshold.
That is what I was saying.
This metadata table will give the
threshold,
but the maths to compare and check
against the threshold is something
framework is doing.
OK and now let me quickly walk you
through the framework.
Now this is a very detailed.
If you see don't panic with the you know
amount of detailed,
it is because I'll tell you the scenarios
that we have tried to handle here.
That is why you see it so big.
The first scenario that we have,
you know we are doing is a regular
scenario meaning every day the batch
executes success scenario.
OK.
There's another scenario which we say
about restart scenario.
Let's say for some reason network issue
or your balance did not match but XYZ.
Any reason the the flow can break in
between correct?
So you have to restart it.
When you restart it, how you handle it?
OK, restart meaning zone to restart.
OK basically think in this way,
your back is still running OK,
you haven't completed your back but still
a job with any field for any reason it
might be OK.
You do some validation,
some you know RND to understand why it
failed and to understood boss let me
restart it.
It will take it.
You know nothing will mess up or even
though it mess ups up the framework will
take care.
So you thought of restarting it.
OK that is another scenario.
Then comes a rerun scenario.
What does rerun scenario means?
Again rerun has is of two type.
Let me go with the first type is zone 1
rerun and the second type is zone 2 rerun.
OK let me first go through the zone 2
rerun.
Zone 2 rerun meaning 10 days.
I mean the batch is executing
successfully for let's say 10 days.
OK on the 11th day you realize but some
transformation rule has gone back.
OK now I have to re redo the exercise.
OK meaning what?
You have to rerun the entire execution
from day one to day 10 or day 11 That is
called a rerun.
Meaning everything has gone fine up till
now but for some XYZ reason you have to
redo the table load.
OK that is what your rerun is about.
OK Zone 2 rerun is about now.
Zone 1 rerun is something like, you know,
they have DMS process,
they have a click process where they
cannot put a checkpoint if something
messes up for three to four days long,
correct.
If they cannot go and go back to the
checkpoint.
So they go ahead and do the entire rerun,
they go and send us the entire data
volume.
So how do we manage that?
So that is what Zone 1 rerun is.
So because instead of 10 record that you
would be expecting today,
you'll get all 110 records.
So how you Zone 2 should process it OK,
so that is about zone 1 rerun OK.
So these are the four or three main
category or regular scenario.
Then your restart scenario,
rerun scenario,
these are the three main categories that
we have tried to achieve in this
framework.
Because there cannot be 4th scenario
where you can think of regular scenario,
restart scenario,
restart meaning failure scenario OK.
So either this or this.
So you have the framework to manage both
the scenarios.
OK, now I'm not.
So this is just things are horizontal
scenarios.
OK, Now within those horizontal scenarios,
there are some vertical scenarios or else
I would say there are someone time
scenarios,
let's say when you're doing catch up for
the one time, OK,
historical load for the one time zone to
first time incremental for one time.
So these are your one time scenarios, OK,
you restart, rerun regular.
These are the scenarios which will happen
very often in your normal cases,
normal days,
but your history catch up or your first
time incremental,
these scenario will happen only one OK,
history catch up.
I'll cover it.
You know, when we go,
when we go through the history loop
scenario.
I'm just giving you a heads up here
because this is again ABC,
everything is is combined at ABC.
So that is why I would tell you these
scenarios are the scenarios that that is
what we have handled and all of that.
You will figure it out in this,
you'll see it in this.
OK,
so far clear with the scenarios that I
just told right now.
OK now let me start with the with
actually this framework.
Now you would have heard me saying it
several times that our load has five
phases,
OK Or else I would say 3 phases mostly
the preload the load and the post load.
So in each job usually have 3 phases, OK.
One is before you load the tables,
while you load the table and after you
load the table.
Your ABC follows all these three phases,
OK.
That is why you see somewhere around
preload as A tag here, Patch, preload,
job, preload,
these two together forms the preload
activity,
then you have the load activity and then
you have the post load activities.
OK now let's say how do you start?
So basically The thing is even though I
start my zone 2, how do I start my zone 2?
My zone 2 will start when my zone one has
completed.
So in my stone branch I'll have a
dependency set on the zone one job.
That was after they complete our job will
trigger OK?
That is a prerequisite to start even any
of our job log or any of our pre job log.
OK,
let's think that the stone branch is
successful,
the zone 1 dependence is successful.
It started.
The first thing that it checks is for a
given job.
OK for a given batch,
sorry for a given batch if the latest
execution of the batch thing that every
day we're loading the jobs correct
today's date and let's say the
expectation is when I start my execution
for my 10th day,
my 9th day job should 9th day batch
should have been completed properly.
OK If it has not completed properly,
meaning what something is mess,
I should not go ahead and corrupt the
system more by executing the batch next
10th day batch correct,
Let me not load it first fix the 9th day
batch what has gone wrong?
It should complete properly and then my
10th batch should trigger.
OK, that is a thought process that we had.
That is why even before it starts,
our zone to load starts at a batch level.
It first goes and checks whether my
previous yes day batch back to that batch
ID is completed or not.
If it is completed then that load
mechanism starts.
If not then it fails and send out a
notification that was something has
failed.
Go ahead and check your system.
OK,
so that is what you'll find it in this
preload prerequisite process.
Assume that everything has you know your
9th day batch has loaded properly.
Now coming to the 10th day batch,
what will it take?
It will take.
So now let me so far these are my
metadata tables correct?
So thing that these tables should have
entry when you execute the process.
The intent of your preload,
the batch preload is to make a entry into
your run status table.
This table OK, how does it make entry?
It takes some of the parameter from here.
Let's say it takes the batch ID.
The application names of these names,
whatever it takes has been listed down
here.
The source name, domain name, target name,
OK,
based on the batch ID from the batch
metadata table, get the status OK.
OK,
so it goes and checks on the batch ID for
which you want to exit.
OK now it checks that till now it has
checked the 9th day batch has been
completed properly.
So for my 10th day it goes ahead and
executes this batch.
OK,
it makes an entry into my batch run
status with this batch ID.
OK Now what does that differentiate?
Not nothing that for all this 10 days
you'll be having one entry for for the
same batch ID.
OK now what differentiates all this batch
ID based on the daily execution?
Is this execution an ID?
This is the only parameter which you
should always hold to,
but any when you have to relate
throughout the day process.
OK, this is a constant value.
With this value your batch run status,
your job run status.
Every single table in your entire status,
you know in your entire runtime tables is
stacked with this particular value
execution run ID.
OK,
so the first thing that it does is it
goes ahead and makes an entry into your
batch and statistic with this execution.
Then I'd OK.
Now, of course,
when you go ahead and execute the batch,
it every batch will have some job stack
for it.
You see, this is the batch ID here,
this is the batch ID here.
Let's say this batch ID for my HR or
let's say producer here.
OK, now producer,
let's say have three jobs stacked to it.
OK, the way we set up the stone branch,
it's a parallel execution,
sequential execution, whatever.
That way we set it up in the stone branch.
The intent is all of these jobs has to
execute properly to close this batch
successfully in my run status table.
OK, now you see a batch has been entered.
So when you as part of preload,
you're this, this value, this value,
this value, OK,
these tactic values get inserted.
OK with the status has started.
So meaning what this batch has started.
Now once the batch has started then comes
a job run status as part of my batch
preload.
What values get inserted there Based on
the execution which job we are executing,
that job ID gets in a loaded here and
with that particular job ID comes your
job run ID OK with the status I started.
So that is all it does as part of your
batch preload and job preload main
activities.
Any questions up till now?
Yeah I sent it.
I have a question here.
So in the Excel SIT reference when you
are seeing that it checks whether the
previous execution for the batch is
complete or not.
Like the 9th execution is complete,
they need process for the next execution.
That check is does on the source batch
entry or the target batch batch entry.
Can you go back to that batch you are
executing?
Let's say you're executing the batch for
the user on your entity.
OK.
So it checks the 9th day producer batch
is completed or not.
So that's respect to the target batch
what we are populating not the source
system.
OK, Yeah,
yeah it is source already you have
executed right.
It is.
So of course source it came till year
because your source is completed
otherwise it,
it would not have come up till year,
correct.
So then another follow up questions when
said that if you're saying the dependence
we have configured in the stone branch
that the source processing is done and
then we are processing our June 1 to June
2,
then we are using that ETEDW source
window table that is 1 table where we are
checking what are the PDF curated from
the source to that, I'll come to that.
OK.
That is why I I took a pause to ask any
questions because this is something I
have to tell about my job reload.
But the bare minimum of which I want to
say here it is as part of job reload
there are two main that get inserted 1 is
it batch run status and job run status.
So after that I'll come to the conflict
table.
So I I took update so just to ask if team
has any questions before I move there.
Sure,
any questions team up till here I'll take
that as a note.
OK, now after the batch has completed,
oh sorry you you have made entry into a
batch run status.
OK then starts the actual job execution.
Now just saying that to execute the job
you need a range to execute correct?
How do you get that range?
That range comes from ETL injection in
the table.
OK, which is the table?
This is the table.
OK so this table contains the range based
on which a job get executed.
Now how this table gets populated?
It should be your first process.
Now after your job run status,
you need an entry into a into a job run
status.
Then this table get populated.
OK,
this table get populated at a source
system level.
I'll tell you how.
Let's say this is a target table as part
of a zone 2.
OK,
but this target table is associated will
be associated with some source table
because zone 1 tables it can be,
1 to one it can be, 1 to many it can be.
It can be in any way correct.
So,
so the intent here is all the tables that
is stacked to this target tables should
be completed or should be listed on here.
OK.
And based on that you'll have the
sourcing windows.
OK.
So if you see the target execution and
I'd the one which I said here,
this execution and ID,
this is the target execution and ID OK,
then you have the batch ID.
Then you have the job ID OK,
then you have the target when whatever
you see target is zone 2 OK,
zone 2 now this is a source.
Then you have the source and an ID source
job status sourcing start sourcing window
OK.
Now the in the idea here is when this
window get populated based on Zone 1
execution, OK,
meaning your sourcing start date time
will be your sourcing the previously
completed sourcing end date time.
Meaning on your 10th day you'll start
with your 9th day you completed OK.
So that ninth day cut time will be your
sourcing start date time for your 10th
day,
and your sourcing end time will be Zone
1's latest job end time.
OK, so far with me.
What does that mean?
If our job has complete?
Let's go with a simple scenario where it
is completed.
OK?
If it is completed,
then you'll have the range and based on
that, your job gets executed.
OK, then comes the complicated scenario.
The one scenario is where you have more
than one source tables associated to a
target OK.
The intent here is both of these should
complete it to start of to start your
zone to target table OK if anything is
failed OK because you get the latest
status.
If your latest status is failed,
meaning what your zone 2 will not
progress, your zone 2 itself will fail,
sending out a notification that zone one
has failed.
The you know the needed whatever the
source that we needed from zone 1 is
failed,
so that is why we will fail zone 2.
The intent here is whenever you start
Zone 2 jobs,
whatever source tables it is associated
with, everything should complete, OK,
And the completed range,
the completed time becomes your sourcing
end time, OK?
Now if you see that is all the scenarios
that we have listed down here,
let's say OK,
there is one more thing I believe all of
you should know by now.
Zone 1 loads their batch 4 times a day,
bare minimum four times a day,
there's stage 2 jobs, OK?
So let's say the best one scenario can be
whatever job that is associated,
all get loaded, OK?
Now whatever jobs it is associated is
loaded in the day but not as part of the
batch 4.
OK And it can be also scenario that not
everything get loaded some get loaded.
There can be another scenario where do
you have mixture of failure and your
success scenario.
OK so the one which I was saying if
something is failed it won't trigger a
zone won't trigger unless both the jobs
is passed here 1 is failed that is why
your zone 2 is failed.
So this particular document list on all
the scenarios that we have accounted for
in this framework to execute the job or
to initiate the job load process.
The you know the take away of this design
is your zone 2 should load only when the
associated zone 1 tables is completed, OK.
And the range is the latest and greatest
execution time of my zone 1 completion
time with me.
Let's say what I mean by that is let's
say you have a relationship table,
local relationship table, OK,
it has two jobs associated with it,
two source tables associated with it not
necessary that both of them will have
that exact millisecond, you know end time.
It can be at 10:31 PM,
this can be at 10:35 PM, correct?
So your this particular job will get
executed or when you source the record
from your this table,
it get executed based on that time range
and the other get executed based on the
other time range.
OK.
So the time range are very much specific
to that particular source table the
intern.
Why I'm stressing upon this is this
particular scenario whichever I discussed
right now,
this will work for incremental loads.
OK, history load, I'll come aside.
I'm not trying to, you know,
confuse you by giving all the information
at this point in time.
All I'm discussing right now is for my
incremental loads.
For my incremental loads,
the take away or the thing that you
should bother is whenever my zone 2 get
loaded or to initiate my zone 2 load,
whatever associated zone 1 tables I have,
everything should be in in the completed
status.
The latest and data should be in
completed status.
If anything is failed,
the zone 2 will be OK.
The zone 2 process will not only initiate
before before it initiates your job will
be OK.
Meaning you're not entering any corrupted
data into your system.
You're you're running only when every
parameters is checked.
OK any questions here?
Yeah.
So into that, I have some question here.
So in this example where we have multiple
sources loading into the same target
table, as you mentioned,
the source window will be specific to
source table only.
Hence can we conclude that in our source
qualified query where we're building,
we need to put multiple window lookups
for multiple source tables?
Yes, that is how it is happening today.
OK, And in this case, as you mentioned,
for example,
if we have a driving table and we have a
lookup table, then in that case,
let's say in our driving table we got the
correct window.
But for the you must not go for the,
you know, driving.
That is a joint scenario.
OK, maybe you ask a question,
maybe I'll answer that look differently
because I don't want to mix that topic
here.
So all right, I'll, I'll,
I'll give it that query sent pass to you
sends it OK, But ask a question.
Yeah, Like in this kind of scenario,
is it OK that we process with the base,
you know,
with having validated with the base table
window PDR,
we process the record with having few
null values and process to target and
reprocess.
Will that not go again?
Again, I, I see where you're going.
We're going to the joints and I will take
that separately.
OK, just think in this way.
The intent here of this table is so if
you have multiple target the source table
associated,
it should be passed to start the agenda,
OK.
The the reason why I don't want to answer
that question right now,
it will be the discussion.
I'll cover that discussion maybe in
subsequent sessions when you go through
the joint scenarios, OK, Sure.
OK.
If nothing, I'll move on.
OK.
That is exactly what is happening in that
field.
OK,
coming to the job to load again we see
the job to load so complicated because
whatever I discussed has lot of notation
combination.
That is what I've been explained yet.
OK, now coming to the job load.
The job load is very simple.
Basically as part of job load thing that.
So before you start job load,
all you have done is you have made
entries in your backstone status in your
job run status in your execution window
that it in windows table.
And there is another I think the
execution log table which says that if
there are any decreases or whatever it
takes that you have to execute that log
table.
You have to make entries OK.
The values that you'll populate in it get
captured in this job load, OK,
and gets populated in your post code, OK,
Now water gets captured here.
The DQ checks,
the Rhode Island checks your count,
the source counts OK.
The balance reconciliation source counts,
the counts, the errors.
The Rhode Island stuff gets captured as
part of the job load process into some
timetable.
OK,
so that is what as part of ABC we do as
part of job load.
Now if you can relate,
that is why you have so many temp tables
as part of DQ RRI captured in your actual
job load process.
OK, now coming to the job post load,
as I said, the post load, the activity,
the post load,
you know the main activity of the post
load is you have made entrance.
Let me show you this.
OK, so let's see here, mid entries,
you see.
This is what your mid entry.
But no record is here, you see.
No count is here, you see any count?
Everything is blank OK.
These counts get populated during the job
post you see as part of a job post.
But all these counts get populated OK as
part of a balance reconciliation.
All the counts get populated as part of a
job rule execution logged.
The count of the status diesel gets
populated OK.
The values from your error table temp
error table goes to into job rule error
detail table.
OK based on the job error detail table,
your job rule execution log gets
populated.
So all those connections and closure of
this table happens in your job post.
What activities?
OK,
like in the intent of me seeing you guys
here is you understand the flow and you
think through how to create the scenarios
while doing testing, OK,
the positive scenarios,
the negative scenarios,
how to ensure that whatever scenarios
you're creating,
what is a mindset of how the ABC should
behave?
That is why I'm stressing upon each
phases and not just telling you, OK,
just go ahead and put in metadata table
will get you know the framework will get
will take care of it.
The the intent here is how the framework
and what is the expected outcome of the
framework.
OK, now if you see the job post load.
OK now if you see the post load I think
this is the job post load.
You load the RA records on the temp RA
table into a main RA table.
OK.
Then you again check if for the job ID,
if there is any DQ checks assigned OK,
with the in the job rule assignment with
the active indicator as well.
OK,
so basically I don't want to go in and
just talk here,
but I the intent here is you have the RA
table, you know, you have the DQ table,
you know.
OK,
so basically just think that you are
entering the temp table from the temp
table.
The data goes and sits in the main table.
If you talk about the DQ,
it sits at a job, sorry at a column level.
So this is a job rule.
The error detail table let's say for a
given record on 2 columns,
if you have DQ checks,
your temp table will hold the information
at the record level.
OK.
But in your error,
the rule I mean this particular error
detail table the entries will be
transposed to show you the result at a DQ
check level.
OK,
so one record becomes 2 records here OK
the same with the RA wherever you have
multiple parent child relationship there
also it becomes two OK.
So the intent here is you drill down at
the most general level into this table,
OK.
Now once this tables get populated based
on how much error you have captured for a
given you know based on a rule.
So that gets captured here for a job role
assignment ID, for job rule assignment ID,
Yeah.
So if all these executions, I mean,
if all the DQ has passed, if not,
then how many DQ has failed,
so and so forth.
The information captured at this level at
a job rule execution log detail, OK.
And also your balance reconciliation
stats level which says that what is a
target count?
What is your source count?
OK, what is a balancing flag?
OK, if it is within the threshold,
if it is if I mean if it is,
why then of course it is within the
threshold.
But if there is balancing flag, OK,
balancing flag mean sorry here it should
be N if it is, if it is not matching yet,
then your balancing flag goes to YN.
OK.
But what is out out the delta model it is
500,
but within is it within the threshold?
If this is a threshold that you have
captured it within your metadata table,
then within the threshold will be by your
end depending upon that.
Now all these information that we have
captured against the balance
reconciliation against the DQ.
So the error detail table both and
deconciles at your job will error job run
step table.
OK, so basically if you see here,
you have a lot of counts here 1 is a
source record count, target insert count,
target update count,
target unchanged count.
And it's reading out.
Basically, this is nothing,
but as part of SCD type 2,
you'll have insert, you'll have update,
you'll have unchanged,
you'll have target error record count,
you'll have target delete record count,
you'll have RII don't think we have RI
here, but yeah,
there's another column called as RI count.
So all these counts get updated in this
table, OK.
And based on that,
you have a flag that gets generated
status.
So basically if there is no DQ errors,
if all the RA issues have been addressed
properly, if there is no balancing,
you know problem, OK,
based on all the status,
if you're the source count and target
count has properly reconciled,
then your status is stacked to complete
it.
OK,
once the status is stacked to complete it
just think that if there are 10 or 100
jobs within that batch,
if all the status TAC to all this hundred
job is TAC to completed,
then only a batch gets completed
successfully.
OK then this gets completed successfully
with the completed status.
Other words if any of the job gets failed,
it gets failed here.
OK,
so that is exactly what has been
explained in this document.
Any questions?
OK, I'll take that as a no,
but if there is any questions you can
reach out to Liya and Aishwarya.
They are the people who are taking care
of this framework and and we have the LLD
also.
Go through the document,
go through the LLD, go through the lucid,
go through this example document.
This will give you a very in depth
understanding of how this game work is
created and what are scenarios that we
expect and how to handle each of these
scenarios.
OK,
if no questions I'll move to the other
topic that is a UTC time zone.
The intent here is when we started this
project,
we got to know that everything was in
different, different time zone OK.
Your data data was in EST,
your snowflake was in PST,
your zone one ABC was in UTC.
OK, so it was, you know,
spread across multiple time zones.
And of course when you have so many time
zones,
it gets very difficult to put that time
frame and do all the exercise.
OK,
so that is where we came to a middle
ground of having everything in UTC,
everything OK.
So why UTC?
Because the ABC that was created by zone
1 till then was in UTC time zone.
OK, the Aurora was in UTC time zone.
That is why the snowflake account that we
are using right now has all been put in
this UTC time zone.
The intent is.
That is why, if you remember,
I always very explicitly talk about this
UTC time zone.
The intent here is whatever calculation
that we do,
whatever extraction that we do,
we always would be very mindful that this
extractions happen on based on the UPC
time, OK, The data within it, OK,
We never got a confirmation from business
or we got alignment.
We put it in this way,
we got alignment from the business saying
that whatever data that you are from that
we are, we are getting,
they don't mess up with the time zone of
that.
OK,
you don't know whether HR is sending me
in one time zone or else producer data is
coming in one time zone or if DLCC is
coming in one time zone.
I don't know what data at the data level
wherever we have date feed,
what time zone it is for then.
So the intent here is keep them as is
because of course we tell my learning
data, correct learning systems.
So if the business is fine with it,
they should be fine with it tomorrow also.
So whatever time zones these data set
follows, keep them as is, OK,
But the way you extract the data, OK,
bring everything in UTC time zone.
So that is why if you remember,
I always said it is and then during the
initial discussions that all the Aurora
table is in my UTC time zone.
OK, so as part of Informatica,
whatever we create also it should be in
UTC time zone.
But then we understood that OK,
my smoke lick anyway,
they're having a source for you,
but written and these projects are
exhibited must not like which it's a time
zone,
so there is no need of explicit
conversion of them.
But the intent here is whatever we
extract OK,
because these are my ABC table dependent
too much are completely ABC table
dependent.
So all the time zones,
all the date feeds should be in times ETC.
Time zone OK convert everything to
maintain to UTC to maintain a single time
zone and ABC and data OK maintain all the
consideration that we have.
This maintain all the audit fields OK
whether it is ABC table or within the
your tables zone 2 tables.
Also we have some audit just correct
audit created by audit updated by.
So those columns data should be
maintained in all UTC time zone, OK,
data extraction logic built on audit
tables and iceberg or Snowflake, OK.
So date data extraction logic will be
built on your audit fields of the iceberg
or Snowflake table, OK,
not on your data field.
That is what I said.
So basically that the way we are doing
the data extraction today,
we are doing it based on the ABC tables
because 11 ABC tables.
So these are itself maintained in your,
you know, in your UTC time.
So you're covered there.
Data refresh and consumption there should
happen based on the table specific audit
fields.
So that is again UTC.
Your AWS STS Blue managed Iceberg table
are all everything is in UTC OK while
only while IDMC and Teradata is in your
EST OK.
How will this impeder come in a while,
But the thought process is everything is
in is in UTC except your ID and C and
current data tables or current data data,
OK and no change in the time zone to the
data wherever we have data time zone
attributes coming from the source.
OK,
So that is why as part of the history
load, OK,
now I'm coming to the data data stuff
here.
OK, So as part of my history load,
that is why we are adding some columns to
it in my process.
Or else I was in the de migrator process
to give me the UTC time zone of when it
of when these tables are getting created
or when this data are getting landed.
So that as part of zone 2 when we set up
the process or we create the ETL,
we check on these UTC tables or UTC
columns rather than on any date columns.
OK,
consider that whatever I'm getting from
Teradata,
those are accesses or my data prints no
change in the time zone to the data
attribute coming from the source.
OK,
So that is why we've added one more
column there.
When we do this as part of history and
catch up extraction,
which tells me the data is there in the
UTC time zone, it gives me a column.
So as we are, as we find time,
when we're adding a extra column to it
which captures a date in the UTC 1.
So that when we extract or we do the data
extraction from zone 2 to the zone 1
tables of this, you know,
zone one parallel data tables that we're
bringing as part of the process,
it has an UTC column to fall back on, OK?
So, so that is the intent.
Everything that we do has to be in UTC,
OK, from your audit column perspective,
but your data perspective,
whatever data field we have,
leave it as is.
No changes to that, OK.
Even though for the USRM back then,
we never knew what they are following.
But the idea here is whatever they do,
still we have to extract the data based
on UTC formula, UTCP range, OK?
And mostly we need to do some conference
search to understand what are these,
what is the time zone based on which this
USRM data are stored or we are bringing
sort of data share.
But the intent is whatever,
whichever format they keep or share,
when we extract the data,
the ET migration window table or the
audit tables, whatever we have,
we have the UTC time zone presented.
OK, any questions?
This is a, this was a very short topic.
So yeah, the intent,
I don't have any scenarios document,
but the expectation here is everything
that we do,
the audit column should be and there's
something that we're also implementing it.
So there's nothing different to that I
can say, OK, any questions?
If we do not have any questions,
there were two more topics that I was
trying to cover.
I think let's cover it tomorrow.
We just have 8 minutes to take more than
that.
But yeah, schema,
we'll cover it in the tomorrow sessions.
OK.
If we have any questions,
please feel free.
We can have use the remaining 7 minutes
to talk about it.
Else we can back up the.
OK.
I'll take the silence as I know.
Please go through the documents,
come up with any question that you have
in the next session so that we can come
up the 1st 10 minutes and then we can
leave that.
OK, thank you.
Thank you.